June 9, 2014

RE: Legislative Assistant (Permanent, Full-Time)

Dear Peter Julian,

I am very interested in continuing my work with the Federal NDP by working with Peter Julian, MP Burnaby--New Westminster at the Parliamentary Office in Ottawa. I am the ideal candidate given my past experiences and knowledge of the NDP party platform. With my multi-dimensional skillset I will be able to make sure Peter Julian is ready for meetings, question period, and responding to constituents. Through my experiences in Federal politics I have acquired an in depth understanding of the foundations, structure, and operations of legislation. While at the national office for the NDP I acted as a liaison between MPs and constituents. I supported 308 candidates during the last federal election by organizing communication between regional offices and the party director, and preparing them on NDP policy before media appearances. I conducted extensive research on ridings throughout Canada to create better phone scripts for volunteers to use to raise funds and increase voter turnout. My experiences working abroad also highlight my capability in project management under minimal supervision. As a teacher I acted as a mentor to my students and managed multiple projects utilizing my excellent communication skills to overcome cultural and language barriers.

My work with the NDP in conjunction with my cross cultural experiences managing diverse projects, programs, and teams has provided me with strong leadership, teamwork, interpersonal, and coordination skills. Several notable skills that speak directly to your needs are the following:

- Excellent organization and project management skills with experiences in fundraising for the Federal NDP on specific riding campaigns including Burnaby--New Westminster. Experience in organizing national conferences in Ottawa with CCIC and Toronto with EWB in awareness of partnerships for global development and the future of Canadian Policy in 2015.
- Extensive experience and proficiency with the Microsoft Suite, campaign software including NDP Vote, Campaign Central, donation processing, billing, and invoicing software.
- Superb verbal and written communication skills proven through my contribution to websites, speech scripts for NDP phone canvassers, conference speaker biographies, minute taking, and drafting final report conclusions. Direct experience reporting to directors, Members of Parliament, and constituent's in-person, over the telephone, and through email correspondence.

These experiences not only highlight my ability to communicate effectively but also manage varying demographics in changing high stress environments with minimal supervision. If I am the successful candidate, you will benefit from a positive, hardworking and driven individual who not only innovates but also takes initiative. Enclosed you will find my resume which provides additional details pertaining to my education and experience.

Thank you for your time and consideration of my application.

Kind regards,

Sahar Hussain

Sahar Hussain

810 Canary Street, Ottawa, ON K4B 1H4 Cell: 647.633.7558 Email: sahar.m.hussain@gmail.com

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

New Democratic Party of Canada (NDP), Ottawa, Canada

2009-2011

- Candidate Support
- Provided 308 candidates running for election with administrative and communications support through correspondence, email creation, campaign resources, and website assistance;
- Produced, shipped, and tracked candidate resource binders, Election Day kits (signage, literature, stickers, and buttons).

Voter Contact/Election Day Organizer for MP Ottawa Center: Paul Dewar

- From Paul Dewar's (PM Ottawa Center) campaign office I managed and organized 100-200 volunteers phone canvassing, door-to-door canvassing, and data entry;
- On Election Day I managed and supervised 300 volunteers working at poll stations, counting ballots, and working as drivers.

Phone Bank Coordinator/Telephone Canvasser

- Spoke with constituents across Canada building awareness of candidates while also managing campaign donations;
- Trained and mentored new employees, created schedules, developed phone scripts, conducted data entry, and produced daily logs on progress.

Education for Students (EforS Co.), Seoul, South Korea

2013

English Teacher

- Taught and managed 100 Korean middle school students ages 9-14 as the after-school programs' sole foreign teacher;
- Increased class enrollment and increased grade average by 15% gaining recognition for our school in the company.

Freobel Eunmult School, Seoul, South Korea

2012-2013

Enalish Teacher

- Taught and managed 100 Korean kindergarten students ages 3-9 and designed curriculum for a creative learning class called 'English Gift';
- Managed 100 students' daily, completed report cards and progress reports, organized school events (eg. field trips, Christmas party) as well as parent teacher conferences.

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

CCIC Policy Conference: Canadian Leadership for a Better World

2013

• Welcomed guest at registration, wrote speaker biographies, and took notes for final reports.

Engineers without Boarders International Policy Conference: RETHINK

2014

• Helped speakers coordinate and facilitate workshops by distributing materials, organizing set up and take down, as well as note taking.

EDUCATION

University of Ottawa

2006-2010

B.A. (Honours) International Development & Globalization